# AASHISH SHARMA

aashish2057@outlook.com | 972-552-4185 | linkedin.com/in/aashish2057/

### **SUMMARY**

Involved Computer Science Student with a variety of experience as a Software Engineer and a Project Manager. Intern at IBM where I gained experience in Load Testing, Robotics, Containers, Cloud, Edge Computing, and Machine Learning Models. Lead teams of 4-5 as PM at the Association for Computing Machinery

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Co-Op Intern, International Business Machines (IBM)

Jan 2020 - Present

- Lead effort to utilize Docker to containerize node-red flows on raspberry-pi, for a shift to edge computing
- Rebuilding predictive R-Square Models through SPSS Modeler and IBM Watson Studio
- Lead testing effort on vision models that resulted in 90% efficiency improvement through the use of JMeter
- Received 17 Certifications from IBM including Data Science, Deep Learning, Node-Red, Agile, Docker, Kubernetes, IBM Watson Studio and React

# Project Manager, Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)

Dec 2019 - Present

- Managed Alakazam Project, a mobile app designed to recognize a movie/TV Show based on recorded audio and return title and other relevant information
- Managed team for Standup, a virtual comedy club where you choose to perform stand-up on-stage or to engage and control the show as the audience
- Implemented Agile methodology into teams through the use of technologies such as GitHub, Trello and Slack
- $\bullet$  Lead Alakazam to 2nd place in Spring 2020

## **PROJECTS**

## DormDash

- Food delivery service tailored specifically towards college students. A mobile application that enables students to order food from campus restaurants, delivered by another student. (Work-in-progress Startup)
- Place 2nd in Fall 2019 ACM Ignite Competition and won audience favorite application

#### Pic3

• Social Media Android Application designed to assist users in helping discover their closest friend, implemented with Android Studio and Google Firebase

# College Grades

• A Website that displayed the median grade for 250 classes at Cornell University, implemented with Google Drive API

### HONORS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service VMs vs. containers, Kubernetes architectural model, key resources, and pods.
- Docker Essentials: A Developer Introduction best practices for using DockerFiles and how to use IBM Cloud Kubernetes Service
- Deep Learning Main concepts of Neural networks, how to implement shallow and deep networks with TensorFlow
- Applied Data Science with Python Can analyze and visualize data with Python using packages like scikit-learn, matplotlib and bokeh
- IBM Blockchain Essentials V2 Understanding of Blockchain and distributed ledger systems, key use cases of Blockchain and how assests can be transferred in a Blockchain network
- $\bullet\,$  Node-Red: basics to bots - understands how to create simple to complex applications in Node-Red
- ACM Ignite Spring 2020 Placed 2nd for best application determined by a panel of professors and industry professionals
- $\bullet$  Academic Excellence Scholarship Honors (AES) The top 10% of UT Dallas Students recieved this award

### **SKILLS**

Languages: C/C++, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, Javascript, React

Technologies: Git, UNIX, REST API, AWS, Azure, IBM Watson, JMeter, Docker, Kubernetes, Node-Red

Tools: Github, Trello, Slack, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Office, Android Studio, IBM Bluemix

Soft Skills: Mentorship, Project Manager, Program Manager, Communication Skills, Public Speaking

## **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Aug 2018 - May 2022

The University of Texas at Dallas

## COURSES

- UT Dallas Introduction to Machine Learning, Numerical Methods in Machine Learning and Data Science, Data Structures and Algorithms, Advanced Algorithm Design and Analysis, Software Engineering, Discrete Mathematics
- Online Meachine Learning Pyhon & R, Web Developer Bootcamp, Azure AI Engineer